Adolph Germer Papers 5256
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Adolph Germer Papers
1945-1947
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Germer, Adolph
5256
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of the papers Adolph Germer collected on his trip to the W.F.T.U. meeting and his membersip of the W.F.T.U. Committee for German Affairs.
5557153
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 07, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 22, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Mr. Germer was born in Welan, Germany In 1881 and came to the United States in 1888. His father was a miner, and Adolph went to work in the coal mines of Staunton, Illinois, when he was eleven years old. He joined the United Mine Workers of America in 1894 and held various offices; among them the United Mine Workers representative to the World Miners Congress in Amsterdam in 1912. He participated in the Colorado strike in 1913.
He joined the Socialist Party in 1900, and was its national secretary from 1916 to 1919. He was arrested, tried and convicted of subversion in the famous trial of 1918. With Eugene V. Debs and Victor L. Berger he wrote the Socialist Party report on the West Virginia Coal Strike in 1913.
In 1933 he joined the Oil Field, Gas Well and Refinery Workers and became an international organizer He participated in the formation of the Congress of Industrial Organizations and was on its staff as an organizer. He was its delegate to the World Federation of Trade Unions meeting in Prague in 1947.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5396 mf: World Federation of Trade Unions Reports and Minutes on Microfilm 5595: World Federation of Trade Unions Records 5809 mf: Adolph Germer Papers on Microfilm
Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Coal mining -- United States; Coal miners -- Labor unions -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Coal mining industry -- United States; Germer, Adolph; World Federation of Trade Unions
5557153
- Personal Correspondence, etc. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- World Federation of Trade Unions (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pamphlets from London Conference, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Feb. 5th-7th in Washington
- Reports to Executive Bureau Meeting, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  September
- Reports of the Meeting of Trade Unions of Trieste, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  October
- Reports to Executive Bureau Meeting, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  December 10th in Paris
- Reports to the General Council Meeting, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  June in Prague
- Resolutions presented to the General Council, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Speeches at Executive Council Meeting, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pan-African Trade Union Conference, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  April 10th-13th
- Minutes of the talks between the A.F.T.U. and the Austrian Trade Union, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Report of the 2nd A.F.T.U. Inquiry Commission on the situation in Germany, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  January to February
- Office of the Military Government for Germany U.S.: Daily excerpts from the Berlin Press, Field Reports, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  February 12th-May 5th
- Freier Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Releases and Publications (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Pamphlets on the economy and trade union movement, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Collected by Mr. Germer during the W.F.T.U. Council Meeting in June